Rory Harder

AOS Philosophy of Language, Philosophy of Mind AOC Epistemology (including formal), Logic

Academic Employment

2021–2022 Postdoctoral Fellow, University of Toronto 2019–2021 Part Time Lecturer, Rutgers University

Education

GRADUATE

2015–2022 PHD in Philosophy, University of Toronto, ABD

Dissertation Title: Joint Action and Communication, With a Focus on Demonstratives

Co-Supervisors: Imogen Dickie and Nate Charlow

Expected Defense: March 2022

VISITING STUDENT in Linguistics, Rutgers University

Host Supervisor: Simon Charlow

Undergraduate

2012–2015 BA (Hons) with High Distinction in Philosophy (Specialist) and History and Philosophy

of Science and Technology (Minor), University of Toronto

2011–2012 Trent University 2010–2011 Fleming College

Papers

PEER-REVIEWED JOURNAL ARTICLES

Accepted Joint Attention and Communication

Inquiry

In Progress

[A paper on the formal semantics of demonstratives]

Revise and Resubmit

Clearing up Clouds: Underspecification in Demonstrative Communication

In Preparation

Presentations

n				
к	FF	FΡ	FF	D

2021	Joint Attention: The Window Into Other Minds?
	American Philosophical Association (APA) Pacific Division Meeting (Symposium)
	Joint Attention and Communication
	Mutual Knowledge 40 Workshop
	A Puzzle About Demonstrative Understanding
	PhiLang 2021
2020	Perspectives in Demonstrative Semantics
	WeSSLLI Student Session; Szklarska Poreba Workshop
2019	The Affiliative Conception of Sense
	Communication, Context, Conversation Workshop
	Clearing up Clouds
	APA Pacific Division Meeting (Colloquium)
2018	Clearing up Clouds
	Context, Cognition, and Communication Conference
2017	Inferences and Neutrality of the Deliberative Ought
	APA Pacific Division Meeting (Colloquium); Canadian Philosophical Association Meeting
	Invited
2020	The Grammar of Reference
	New York Philosophy of Language Workshop
2017	Inferences and Neutrality of the Deliberative Ought
,	Semantics Research Group (University of Toronto Department of Linguistics); Computa
	tional Linguistics Seminar (University of Toronto Department of Computer Science)
	Teaching
	reaching
	Course Instructorships at Rutgers University
2020	Introduction to Formal Reasoning and Decision Making (1st year, Online)
2019	Introduction to Formal Reasoning and Decision Making (1st year)
	Course Instructorships at the University of Toronto
2020	Special Topics in Philosophy: Frege's Puzzle (3rd year, Online)
2019	Issues in Philosophy of Mind: Perception and Conception (3rd year)

Rory Harder 2

OTHER

Super-TA for the Socrates Project (Supervising Undergraduate TAs, University of Toronto)
Philosophy Don (Tutor and Residence Assistant, Trinity College, University of Toronto)

TEACHING ASSISTANTSHIPS AT THE UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Ancient Philosophy (2nd year), 17th- and 18th-Century Philosophy (2nd year), Introduction to Philosophy (1st year), Knowledge and Reality (2nd year), Probability and Inductive Logic (2nd year), Introduction to Symbolic Logic (2nd year, online)

Scholarships & Awards

GRADUATE

2020–2021 Doctoral Completion Award (\$14,859)

Merit-based award for graduate students at the University of Toronto.

2019–2020 Ontario Graduate Scholarship (\$15,000)

Merit-based scholarship for graduate students at public universities in Ontario.

SSHRC CGS Michael Smith Foreign Study Supplement (\$6,000)

Awarded annually to 125 Canadian graduate students in the social sciences and humanities.

2016–2019 SSHRC Joseph-Armand Bombardier CGS Doctoral Scholarship (\$105,000)

Awarded to about 22% of applicants, who are Canadian graduate students in the social sciences and humanities.

Undergraduate

2012

2017

The George Kennedy Scholarship, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto Awarded annually to a graduating philosophy student.

Socrates Award, Department of Philosophy, Trent University

Awarded annually to a philosophy student in each of the second and third years.

Professional Activity

2020 Graduate Student Coordinator for Institutional Strategic Initiative in Language and Cognition, University of Toronto

STUDENT PARTICIPANT at 29th European Summer School in Logic, Language, and Information

STUDENT PARTICIPANT at Seventh North American Summer School on Logic, Language, and Information

Referee and Commentater for Philosophy Graduate Student Conference, University of Toronto

Rory Harder

Dissertation

Title

Joint Action and Communication, With a Focus on Demonstratives

Summary

My dissertation develops a view of human communication according to which it is the joint activity of making sense of one another. I draw upon recent philosophical and psychological work on joint attention to show how my view provides a superior successor to orthodox Griceanism. I also motivate my view by explaining how there can be successful communication, despite the interlocutors not settling on one or another object as referent of a used demonstrative. Finally, I address the challenge, which arises for any broadly Gricean view of communication, of explaining what is special about linguistic communication. My answer focuses on demonstratives and is based upon a formal semantics for them and related expressions that I develop within the tradition of dynamic semantics.

References

Research

IMOGEN DICKIE, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: imogen.dickie@utoronto.ca

NATE CHARLOW, Associate Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: nate.charlow@utoronto.ca

PHILIP KREMER, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: philip.kremer@utoronto.ca

Teaching

RACHEL BARNEY, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: rachel.barney@utoronto.ca

Contact Information

E-mail rory.harder@mail.utoronto.ca https://www.roryharder.com

Address Philosophy Department, 170 St. George St., Toronto, ON, Canada M5R 2M8

Rory Harder 4